Chapter
1.
A
Farm,
a
Family,
and
a
Gathering
Crisis.
Abigail
Adams
did
not
enter
history
through
a
battlefield.
She
entered
it
through
a
household,
library,
and
a
habit
of
paying
fierce
attention.
She
was
born
Abigail
Smith
in
Weymouth,
Massachusetts,
into
a
New
England
world
shaped
by
family,
faith,
work,
and
ideas.
Girls
in
that
world
were
not
usually
offered
the
formal,
classical
education
available
to
many
boys.
Abigail
never
attended
college
and
did
not
receive
systematic
schooling
in
the
way
leading
men
did.
Yet,
she
educated
herself
through
reading,
conversation,
and
close
observation.
That
difference
mattered
for
the
rest
of
her
life.
She
learned
outside
institutions,
and
because
of
that,
she
often
saw
their
limits
more
clearly.
In
1764,
she
married
John
Adams,
then
a
rising
young
lawyer.
Their
marriage
became
one
of
the
most
remarkable
partnerships
in
early
American
history.
It
was
affectionate,
argumentative,
practical,
and
intellectually
alive.
John
admired
Abigail's
judgment.
Abigail
expected
to
be
taken
seriously.
Across
the
long
years
ahead,
especially
when
politics
kept
them
apart,
their
letters
would
become
one
of
the
best
records
of
the
revolutionary
era.
At
first,
however,
life
did
not
look
like
national
history.
It
looked
like
local
responsibility.
Abigail
managed
homes
in
Braintree
and
later
near
Boston,
raised
children,
supervised
labor,
worried
about
money,
and
handled
the
thousand
ordinary
burdens
that
keep
a
family
standing.
This
is
exactly
why
she
matters
so
much.
Revolutions
are
often
remembered
through
declarations
and
uniforms,
but
most
people
experience
political
crisis
through
rent,
crops,
illness,
shortages,
distance,
and
fear.
Abigail
understood
the
public
crisis
through
private
pressure.
Massachusetts
in
the
1760s
and
early
1770s
was
one
of
the
hottest
centers
of
colonial
resistance
to
British
policy.
Taxes,
customs
enforcement,
soldiers
in
Boston,
and
arguments
over
Parliament's
authority
all
sharpened
tension.
Abigail
watched
the
quarrel
grow
not
as
a
distant
spectator,
but
as
the
wife
of
a
man
increasingly
drawn
into
public
leadership.
John
Adams
defended
British
soldiers
after
the
Boston
Massacre
because
he
believed
law
required
it.
He
then
moved
steadily
toward
resistance
as
imperial
policy
hardened.
Abigail
watched
him
change,
and
she
changed
with
the
times
as
well.
Her
letters
show
that
she
was
no
passive
partner
simply
waiting
to
hear
what
men
had
decided.
She
formed
opinions,
offered
advice,
and
judged
events
sharply.
She
could
see
hypocrisy
quickly,
especially
when
lofty
language
hid
selfishness
or
weakness.
She
also
possessed
a
practical
temperament
that
public
men
often
lacked.
She
knew
what
decisions
cost
once
they
reached
kitchens,
farms,
and
children.
This
ability
to
connect
politics
with
lived
reality
made
her
unusually
valuable.
John
Adams
was
often
away
on
legal
and
political
work.
Abigail
therefore
managed
family
affairs
under
increasing
strain.
She
handled
finances,
tracked
prices,
directed
workers,
and
tried
to
maintain
stability
while
Massachusetts
drifted
toward
upheaval.
This
was
skilled
labor,
not
background
scenery.
As
imperial
tensions
deepened,
the
Adams
household
became
part
of
the
larger
story.
John
went
to
the
Continental
Congress.
Abigail
stayed
behind
to
hold
family
life
together
while
watching
the
colony
move
toward
war.
The
distance
between
them,
measured
in
roads
and
weather
danger,
turned
letters
into
lifelines.
Those
letters
matter
because
they
preserve
a
revolution
from
a
different
angle.
They
record
a
woman
thinking
hard
while
epidemics
moved
through
towns,
armies
gathered,
and
ordinary
routines
became
uncertain.
Abigail
wrote
about
ideas,
but
she
also
wrote
about
inoculation,
crop
conditions,
shortages,
and
neighborhood
fears.
This
combination
is
precisely
what
makes
her
indispensable
to
history.
She
keeps
politics
attached
to
consequence.
She
also
keeps
the
founding
generation
from
looking
too
polished.
Abigail
did
not
flatter
automatically.
She
could
admire
courage
and
still
notice
vanity.
She
believed
in
liberty,
but
she
had
little
patience
for
men
who
spoke
of
rights
while
ignoring
injustice
close
at
hand.
Long
before
many
later
readers
began
asking
harder
questions
about
the
American
founding,
Abigail
was
already
asking
some
of
them
from
inside
the
founding
generation
itself.
By
the
time
revolution
began
in
earnest,
she
had
become
something
rare.
A
political
thinker
who
did
not
hold
office,
a
strategist
of
domestic
survival,
and
an
observable
who
could
see
both
the
grandeur
and
the
strain
of
events
at
once.
The
war
would
test
all
those
qualities.
John
would
spend
long
stretches
away
from
home.
Abigail
would
manage
children,
money,
and
danger
under
wartime
conditions.
The
British
Army
and
Navy
would
move
near
enough
for
fear
to
feel
immediate.
And
through
all
of
it,
she
would
continue
to
write,
recording
not
only
what
happened,
it
felt
like
when
history
came
close
enough
to
shake
the
windows.