Chapter
The
Overdue
Book
Problem
The
Nutville
Library
had
a
problem
with
returns.
Not
ordinary
returns.
Not
one
book
under
the
couch
returns.
An
avalanche
of
overdue
books.
Miss
Maple,
the
librarian,
had
sent
reminder
notes
to
the
whole
town.
Some
books
were
under
beds,
some
were
in
wagons.
One
cookbook
had
somehow
been
borrowed
by
the
Goops,
and
three
adventure
novels
were
currently
being
used
to
level
a
wobbly
table
at
the
mayor's
office.
Miss
Maple
sighed
into
a
stack
of
paperwork.
Books
belong
on
shelves,
not
under
casseroles.
Nutty,
Mama,
and
Papa
were
standing
at
the
desk
with
a
pile
of
slightly
late
books
and
one
extremely
late
atlas
that
Papa
claimed
had
hidden
under
a
blanket
all
by
itself.
"What
the
library
needs,"
Nutty
said,
eyeshining,
"is
a
faster
return
system."
Miss
Maple
froze.
Define
faster.
"Immediate!"
Nutty
said.
"Townwide!
Efficient!
Exciting!"
Grandma
Nut
Wobble,
who
had
been
quietly
selecting
a
gardening
book,
closed
her
eyes.
"The
library
does
not
need
exciting!"
Nutty
already
had
the
notebook
out.
He
drew
a
tube,
launch
ramp,
a
receiving
basket,
and
a
little
arrow
labeled
"Books
go
whoosh!
Knowledge
arrives!"
Mama
gasped
happily.
"A
book
rocket!"
Miss
Maple
clutched
the
desk.
"Books
are
not
supposed
to
whoosh!"
Papa
considered
this.
Some
adventure
books
seem
like
they
want
to.
The
more
nutty
explained,
the
worse
and
better
it
sounded.
He
wanted
a
return
launcher
in
the
town
square
that
could
send
books
directly
to
the
library's
new
rooftop
basket.
Overdue
books
would
zoom
home,
shelves
would
refill
faster,
reading
would
become
more
aerodynamic.
Miss
Maple
was
horrified,
but
she
was
also
tired,
and
the
overdue
pile
was
large
enough
to
qualify
as
furniture.
"One
demonstration,"
she
said
at
last,
"with
a
soft
basket
and
absolutely
no
encyclopedias."
Nutty
saluted,
"You
won't
regret
this."
Grandma
muttered,
"I
will."