Chapter 3.
Blackjack Varn's Trick.
Dust did not have time for a proper
plan, so she settled for the kind that
involved speed, rooftops, and a high chance of
regretting things later.
She rode Bishop straight through town.
At the dry goods store, she stood in
the stirrups and caught the edge of an
awning.
At the tailors, she climbed from awning to
balcony.
From the balcony, she hauled herself onto the
roof of the boarding house.
Someone below shouted, Marshall, that seems unsafe.
Then don't copy me, she shouted back.
Wind struck her as she reached the highest
roof on Main Street.
Up there, the floating stagecoach looked even stranger.
The body was built like a rich man's
travel coach, but brass pipes ran along its
sides.
Iron tanks clung to the rear axle.
At the roofline, folded veins snapped in the
wind like metal feathers.
Smoke hissed from a crooked stack near the
driver's box.
It was not elegant.
It was an airborne argument with common sense.
The three fools on the saloon roof had
finally managed to snag one rope around the
back wheel.
They cheered too early.
The wheel spun, wrapped the rope, and yanked
them belly first across the shingles in a
single howling line.
Dust stepped onto the saloon sign, balanced once,
and judged the distance.
This is going to be annoying, she told
the sky.
Then she jumped.
For one terrible heartbeat, there was nothing under
her boots.
Then she hit the coach roof hard enough
to bite her tongue.
She slid halfway to the edge, grabbed a
brass whale, and hauled herself flat while the
coach rocked wildly.
All right, she muttered.
I'm here.
Everybody can stop being dramatic.
A hatch in the roof banged open below
her.
Steam belched upward.
Dust dropped through into the coach.
The inside looked like a gambling hall and
a machine shop had gotten into a fistfight.
Velvet seats were torn out to make room
for gears, levers, gauges, and two large copper
boilers that rattled with dangerous enthusiasm.
Silver sacks were piled nearly to the ceiling.
At the front, one man rustled to controls.
Black Jack Varn wore black gloves, a black
vest, and a grin so sharp it seemed
like part of the weaponry.
His hair was slicked back, his mustache curved
like quotation marks around a joke nobody trusted.
On his shoulder sat a green parrot with
a missing tail feather.
The parrot took one look at Dust and
screamed, Law!
Afternoon, Varn, Dust said.
Black Jack Varn did not turn around right
away.
He only yanked a lever, cursed at a
gauge, and said, Marshal Calloway, I ought to
be insulted.
You boarded my invention without buying a ticket.
You dropped half your ticket money on the
town.
Now he looked over, his grin wild.
Temporary complication.
You call dynamite under the water tower temporary
too?
I call it insurance.
Dust's hand drifted toward her revolver.
Vor noticed and laughed.
Go ahead and draw, he said.
One stray shot and this one machine comes
down in splinters and steam.
Dust believed him.
The coach bucked sideways.
One of the boilers whined like it had
seen the future and disliked it.
You built this?
Dusk asked.
Designed it.
Built it.
Improved it.
The roads belong to sheriffs and toll men
and weather.
The sky belongs to the first fool bold
enough to take it.
The parrot bobbed its head.
Bold fool!
Vaughn flecked a switch.
The folded beams outside snap and vibrate.
The coat clanged another few feet.
You're not clean, you're friend.
You're circling!
I touched him, going scattered at the beach.
Crosswind caught a speed-rise over the middle of
the gorge.
Nothing I can't say.
Coach looked tall enough to knock a foot
back into the wall.
What a smile about you.
You're a star-doller.
Don't reach for another moment.
Don't reach for a star-study.
Get kids with the receptors you can use.
You're not a good kid.
You're a good kid.
Thank
you.
So, Fast and dirty.
Dust blocked one swing, took another to the
ribs, and answered with a hard right that
snapped his head sideways.
He staggered into a wheel mounted on the
front column.
The parrot landed on top of it and
shrieked, We're doomed!
Outside, the green clouds thickened.
Dust didn't notice them before from the street,
but up here they looked worse.
A spinning storm wall, green as bottle glass,
rolling in low over the plains.
Vaughn wiped blood from the corner of his
mouth.
He'll paint a bad time to interfere, Marshall.
Dust glanced through the front glass.
No, she said.
You picked a bad day to fly.